[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to this
business central launch event session on
a new API endpoint the tenant discovery
endpoint. Um this is a small feature and
a continuation to the uh S2S app
authentication for the admin center API
that we built some time ago. Um, we've
seen many partners use their their apps
to automate administrative operations
across their customer environments in
different tenants. Uh, but one thing
that was still missing was a discovery
endpoint that would give you a list of
tenants uh to which that app has access.
Um, so if your partner managing
environments in many different customer
tenants, you'd have to keep a list of
those tenants somewhere that that app
could refer to to run then to then run
operations across all customer
environments.
Um, in this release wave, we fixed it
with an API endpoint that we call the
tenant discovery endpoint. And it's
probably better to just show you what it
does rather than go through some more
slides. So, let me jump into a demo
right away. So here I have a little
sample logic app that uh every day gets
the list of tenants that that the app
that is authenticating us can use. Gets
the environments for those apps. Checks
whether those environments have
available app updates and if so installs
those app updates. So just to have a
look at the logic app itself. I'll go
into edit here. I can see here that I
have a logic app that have has a
recurrent run. So it triggers every X
period and then it starts with a HTTP
call to get the manageable tenants in
the tenant admin center. So here opening
this first action of this logic app I
can see that it's indeed calling the
manageable tenants API which would mean
that this logic app would start with a
list of tenants that can be managed by
the app that this action is
authenticated as. Then once it gets
those apps, it parses the JSON response
and then for each of the tenants that it
receives, it will get the environments,
parses that response, checks for
updates, and then further on it would
then install those updates. And of
course, you can add additional
conditions to say only install the app
updates if if some condition is true. To
have a look at at what this looks like
in action, we're going back to the uh
app overview page and we're looking at a
recent run that succeeded. So you can
see here indeed it triggered and this
API call here succeeded. It's the same
endpoint the manageable tenants
endpoint and you can see here it indeed
simply returned a list of tenants that
can be managed by this app. This was
just a simple scenario where this API
endpoint is already saving time by
listing the number of tenants that can
be managed. Um, we have many partners
for which this will be a more powerful
enabler that have more advanced
automation across their customer
environments and we're excited to see
what you do with it. Thank you for
watching.